Zhao Shu

Senior Java Developer

Chengdu, CN zhaobenben007@googlemail.com +86 159 2810 1615

My top technical skills focus on the Web Engineering and Algorithm Design in the fields of E-Commence and financial systems as of a bank.

My previous project experiences span across products Searching and Recommendation Algorithm implementations based on Natural Language Processing for Chinese, Machine Learning and Indexing; bank's Content Management System involving Responsive design, Accessibility and Security improvements, SEO and Web Performance Tuning and its underlying infrastructure setup and management such as DNS, Load Balance and CDN, and automation testing for Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment.

Java is my major programming language for 10+ years, and I've been practicing JavaScript and Python for 2+ years.

As of my soft skills, I'm keen to solve the various problems from scratch and I'm an eager learner for any brand-new challenges. I loves to work with people, motivating a team and walking the talk. Life is in flux, and I enjoy adapting to the keep-changing environments.

Work Experience

Chapter Lead

ANZ - Chengdu, CN July 2016 to September 2018

Create the "Pangaroo" team comprised of members from Melbourne and Chengdu working on the Agile methodology with the goal to build ANZ websites with data analytics and A/B test embedded for the purpose of marketing. Till now 60-plus responsive websites

have been live, including ANZ's portal site https://institutional.anz.com for the Institutional department, https://propertyprofilereport.anz.com for the Home Loan department, https://www.wealth.anz.com for the Wealth department and https://bluenotes.anz.com for the ANZ newsroom.

Strengthen the test team with the automation testing techniques, in which a Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery process is in use and any codebase update will trigger an automatic Docker-based integration test against the code quality, accessibility, security, visual difference from the baseline and an API-driven test if there is an interaction with the backbone system before the automatic deployment to the aimed server. Furthermore, a daily health check on all the live websites will be carried out on an hourly basis to send mail notifications to the team if there are any emergencies, e.g. server malfunctions.

As we've categorized so many of the visual designs of our websites into various reusable components, such as hero banner, header, footer, product list, etc... which are indexed in our product catalogue website "https://pangaroo.anz", that any other department can simply reference and construct a typical website with the listed building blocks, and with the automatic testing in place, we've saved our effort for more innovations and PoCs (Proof of Concepts) in the team. These innovations include below items:

- A Slack-based chatbot "Know It All" used as an ANZ internal wikipedia, with which ANZ employees can make an enquiry about HR policies, IT problem solutions and the meanings for a mass of acronyms mentioned a lot in the banks.
- A blockchain-based system "I Appreciate", where the ANZ employees can appreciate for the help they've obtained from each other in exchange of "Social Coins".
- A PWA (Progressive Web App)-based tool "Harmony", with which any Scrum squad members can use their own phones to make an estimation of each story simultaneously and anonymously in each sprint.
- A Activiti-based workflow framework, in which the digital application forms can be customized with various reusable processes, such as the addition of the form checker role before the data submitted by the clients flows into the backbone system.
- A Micro-Service based property sales price lookup system, where the service of price lookup and the service of the home loan application assessment are decoupled in two teams to improve the team collaboration efficiency.

Senior Java Developer

ANZ - Chengdu, CN July 2014 to June 2016

Develop the backbone E-Statement system, which facilitates the credit card clients to switch off the paper statement for the digital one.

Develop as a full-stack for the websites including https://www.women.anz.com, https://www.wome

Senior Software Engineer

Newegg Inc - Chengdu, CN November 2011 to June 2014

For "Blue Whale" luxury goods sales platform, I implement the product searching and recommendation algorithms based on Machine Learning, e.g. classifier and tagging, and String Comparison, e.g. similarity matrix computing, and Natural Language Processing for Chineses sentences. Besides, I develop an account management system to manage the authentication and authorization of various roles: e.g. administrator, brand manager, end user, etc. Moreover I develop a comment management system, in which moderators can monitor the comments with the functions such as filtering through the black list.

For "Global Data Center" project, I build up a system comprised of almost all the consumer products on sales in the platforms like Newegg, Amazon, Tiger Direct, Best Buy, in which the attributes of each product can be extracted and compared with one another. The framework is based on Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing and String Comparison.

Education

Master in Applied Computer Science

Freiburg Universitaet

September 2007 to July 2011

Double Bachelor in Software Engineering & Japanese Literature

Sichuan University

September 2003 to July 2007

Skills

Java J2EE, Java, Spring, Hibernate, J2EE, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, HTML 5, CSS3, Javascript, Database Management, AWS, Akamai, Docker, Python, CI/CD, Automation Test

Certifications/Licenses

Scrum Master

Additional Information

Linguistic skills

- English IELTS 7.5
- German Reading and Writing
- Japanese Double Bachelor